Finding Aid for the Christopher Coover Collection of Theater Broadsides, 1790-1868
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Christopher Coover Collection of Theater Broadsides, 1790-1868
Mus. Arc. 58
Coover, Chris
1 box (18 items)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Collection of seventeen (and one duplicate) theater broadsides dating from 1790-1868 for performances in Boston, Massachusetts (2), London, England (14), and York, England (1).
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Purchased in New York City by Christopher Coover, circa 1975-1976. Given to the Music Library by Christopher Coover, December 2010.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
Digital images of the broadsides combined with text transcriptions are linked from the container list.
Biographical Note
Christopher Coover received his Bachelor of Arts degree in Music from the State University of New York at Buffalo in 1973. While at the university he studied lute. After leaving Buffalo he moved to New York City where he earned a degree in library science at Columbia University in 1983. He began working for the noted auction house, Christie's, in 1980 and at this writing is a senior vice president and specialist in manuscripts at Christie’s in New York City. He has also served as an appraiser on the popular television program, Antiques Roadshow.
Historical Note
Theater broadsides, or playbills, contain more than just a record of theatrical performances and practices. They also reflect contemporaneous cultural tastes and often contain allusions to historical events. One aspect of the information that is most easily appreciated is the repertoire of music and plays stated in the playbills. Shakespeare is the most-performed playwright in this collection that spans the years 1790-1868. Performances of fourteen of his plays are advertised on eleven of the playbills for a total of twenty performances. There are more than seventy works named in the collection and approximately four hundred names, including managers, singers, dancers, authors, actors, printers, and other performers. Notable names include Henry R. Bishop, John Braham, Angelica Catalani, Christy Minstrels, Mrs. Faucit (Harriet Elizabeth Diddear), Fanny Elssler, Catherine Hayes, Charles Benjamin Incledon, Robert Keeley, William Macready, Henry Marston, Samuel Phelps, John Sinclair, Catherine Stephens, John Vandenhoff, and Benjamin Webster.
Represented on the playbill for the 1868 Boston Theatre performance is a rare American performance by French performer, Jules Leotard (1842-1870). Leotard is usually credited with being the first trapeze artist. The article of clothing, the leotard, is named after the costume he made famous and the George Leybourne song, The Daring young man on the flying trapeze, was inspired by Leotard.
The collection contains nine playbills from the Sadler's Wells Theatre. They represent the entire span of years (1844-1862) during which the theater was managed and directed by Samuel Phelps. The first playbill in the sequence, dated 11 August 1844, is presumably the first playbill for the theater under the new management of Phelps and Mary Warner. Its verso contains a lengthy statement about the goals for the theater with reference to the 1843 Theatre Regulation Act. The nine playbills for Sadler's Wells give proof to Phelps' goals for a higher level of programming. Over the course of his thirteen-year management there were thirty performances of Shakespeare plays. The collection also contains a playbill for a performance by Samuel Phelps at Sadler's Wells on 25 October 1862. This was after he had resigned from the theater and the playbill advertises an upcoming performance as being his farewell benefit.
The playbill for Sadler's Wells dated 22 September 1849 contains an unusual statement: "... this evening, Friday, Sept. 21st, there will be no performance, in consequence of the Churchwardens of the Parish having appointed the day as one of humiliation and prayer". This is most likely due to the cholera epidemic that killed more than 33,000 people in Great Britain in 1849, including approximately 13,000 people in London.
Scope and Content Note
This collection of seventeen theatrical broadsides contains examples from the Boston Theatre (1) and Tremont Theatre (1) in Boston, Massachusetts, the Royal Theatre (3) and Royal Italian Opera (1), Covent Garden and the Sadler's Wells Theatre (9), and the Saint James' Theatre (1) in London, England, and the Theatre Royal (1) in York, England.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by city of origin and then alphabetically by theater. Multiple broadsides under a single theater are arranged chronologically.
I. Boston, Massachusetts, United States
II. England
Container List
- Boston, Massachusetts, United States 1840-1868, I.; Item 1-Item 2
  - Boston Theatre (Washington Street, Boston, Mass.), 10 November 1868, 1 broadside; 51 cm. x 21 cm. (Box 1, Item 01)
    Reduced title transcription: Boston Theatre … J. B. Booth, Lessee and manager: Brief engagement of the wonder of the world! The unapproachable and only Leotard who will appear in his great Zampillaerostation, or Flight in the Air! Which will be preceded on Tuesday, Nov. 10th … by the popular sensation play, entitled After Dark ... F. A. Searle, Job Printer, 118 Washington Street, Boston
    Works named:
    Boucicault, Dion, 1820-1890: After dark
    Personnel named include:
    Louis Aldrich ( Aldrich, Louis, 1843-1901)
    J. B. Booth ( Booth, Junius Brutus, 1821-1883)
    Stuart Clarke (possibly same as John Stuart Clarke) ( Clarke, Stuart, 19th cent.)
    S. H. Forsberg ( Forsberg, S. H. (Shirley Harold))
    Shirley France ( France, Shirley Henry, 1839-1879)
    J. F. Hagan ( Hagan, J. F. (James F.))
    Jules Leotard ( Leotard, Jules)
    A. Leonard ( Leonard, Ambrose)
    Jas. Lewis ( Lewis, James, d. 1896)
    D. J. Maguinnis ( Maguinnis, D. J. (Daniel J.), 1834-1889)
    Miss Rachel Noah ( Noah, Rachel, 1845-1879)
    J. D. Russell (real name J. R. Clark; also known as Clarke, Russell, J. R. Dutton, R. Arnott, Russell Girard) ( Russell, J. D., 19th cent.)
    J. Scott ( Scott, J., 19th cent.)
    F. A. Searle (printer) ( Searle, Frederick A.)
    A. Soup ( Soup, A., 19th cent.)
    Mr. C. R. Thorne, Jr. ( Thorne, Charles Robert, 1840-1883)
    Miss Rachel Noah ( Noah, Rachel, 1845-1879 )
    Miss Helen Tracy ( Tracy, Helen, fl. 1870-1908)
    H. A. Weaver ( Weaver, H. A. (Henry A.), 19th cent.)
    S. J. Willis ( Willis, S. J. (Sarell J.) )
  - Tremont Theatre (Boston, Mass.), 7 September 1840, 1 broadside; 36 x 16 cm. (Box 1, Item 02)
    Reduced title transcription: Tremont Theatre: First appearance in Boston of Mademoiselle Fanny Elssler … She will make her debut in the grand ballet of La Tarentule! And will appear in her celebrated dance of the Cracovienne!: First appearance of Mons. J. Sylvain from the Royal Academie, Paris … This evening, Monday, Sept. 7th, 1840, will be presented … La Tarentule … to be followed by the farce, in one act, called The Captain is Not Amiss! ... The performance will commence with the prelude of the Bath Road … The comedy of Nicholas Nickleby is in revival: Mr. and Mrs. Creswick are engaged, and will shortly appear … Eastburn's Press, 18 State Street [Boston]
    Wilks, Thomas Egerton, 1812-1854: Captain is not amiss
    Poole, John, 1786?-1872: Intrigue, or, The Bath Road
    Everpoint, 1810-1856. Nicholas Nickleby
    Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870. Nicholas Nickleby
    Mr. Andrews ( Andrews, George H., 1798-1866)
    Mrs. Ayling ( Ayling, W. L., Mrs., b. 1819)
    Mr. Benson ( Benson, Mr., 19th cent.)
    Miss Boquet ( Boquet, Miss)
    Mr. Creswick ( Creswick, William, 1813-1888)
    Mrs. Creswick ( Creswick, Elizabeth, d. 1876)
    Eastburn's Press
    Mrs. Fanny Elssler ( Elssler, Fanny, 1810-1884)
    Mr. S. D. Johnson ( Johnson, Samuel D., 1813-1863)
    Mr. Leman ( Leman, Walter Moore, b. 1810)
    Muzzy ( Muzzy, Charles, d. 1852)
    Mons. J. Sylvain ( Silvain, James, d. 1856)
    Mrs. W. H. Smith ( Smith, Sarah Riddle, 1808-1861)
- England, 1790-1862, II.; Item 3-Item 17
  Arranged into two subseries:
  A. London
  B. York
  - London, 1814-1862, II. A; Item 3-Item 16
    Arranged into three subseries:
    Covent Garden (including its Royal Italian Theatre)
    Theatre Royal, Sadler's Wells
    Saint James' Theatre
    - Covent Garden Theatre, 1814-1860, 2. A. 1; Item 3-Item 6
      - Covent Garden Theatre 11 March 1814, 1 broadside; 31 x 18 cm. (Box 1, Item 03)
        Reduced title transcription: Theatre Royal Covent-Garden: This present Friday, March 11, 1814 will be performed a Grand Selection from the compositions of the most favorite authors, ancient and modern. In which Madame Catalani will sing Holy, holy, Lord, Sul margine, with new variations by Pucitta, the Duetto Ah perdonna, with Mr. Braham, and at the end of the first act, the national air of God save the King … Between the first and second parts, Mr. S. Wesley will (by desire) repeat his new concerto for the organ and on Wednesday will be performed the first act of the Creation, composed by Dr. Haydn, with two grand miscellaneous acts … The new dramatick romance called The Wandering Boys, or, the Castle of Olival, continuing to be well received … will be repeated tomorrow. The new opera of the Farmer’s wife continues to be received with the most enthusiastic applause … and will be repeated on Tuesday next. Tomorrow, the Beggar’s opera, compressed into two acts … After which, the Farce of The Pannel … Shakspeare’s tragedy of King Richard the Third will be performed on Monday … to which will be added the Melo-Drama of Aladdin; or, The Wonderful lamp. On Tuesday … the new opera of The Farmer’s wife with the new pantomime of Harlequin & the swans; or, the Bath of beauty … [Printed by] E. Macleish, 2 Bow Street.
        Bishop, Henry R. (Henry Rowley), Sir, 1786-1855: Aladdin
        Bishop, Henry R. (Henry Rowley), Sir, 1786-1855: Farmer's wife
        Gay, John, 1685-1732: Beggar's opera
        Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809: Schöpfung
        Kemble, John Philip, 1757-1823: Pannel
        Kerr, John, fl. 1814-1834: Wandering boys
        Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616: King Richard III
        Ware, W. (William): Harlequin and the swans, or, The bath of beauty
        Mr. Ashley ( Ashley, General Christopher, 1769-1818)
        Mr. Barrymore ( Barrymore, W. (William), d. 1845)
        Mr. Braham ( Braham, John, 1774-1856)
        Madame Angelica Catalani ( Catalani, Angelica, 1780-1849)
        Mr. Conway ( Conway, William Augustus, 1789-1828)
        Mr. Duruset ( Duruset, John, 1796-1843)
        Mr. Egerton ( Egerton, Daniel, 1772-1835)
        Mrs. Faucit ( Diddear, Harriet Elizabeth, 1789-1857)
        Mr. Garbett ( Garbett, Mr.)
        Mr. Incledon ( Incledon, Charles Benjamin, 1763-1826)
        Mrs. Jordan ( Jordan, Dorothy, 1761-1816)
        Mr. Kellner (probably Kellner, Ernest Augustus, 1792-1839)
        E. Macleish ( Macleish, E. (Elizabeth)) Note: Macleish's name is confirmed as Elizabeth in Old Bailey Proceedings Online ( www.oldbaileyonline.org, version 6.0, 23 April 2012), December 1799, trial of GEORGE PARR (t17991204-21).
        Mrs. Powell ( Powell, Jane, ca. 1761-1831)
        Pucitta ( Pucitta, Vincenzo, 1778-1861)
        Miss Rennell ( Rennell, Miss, d. 1816)
        Mrs. Salmon ( Salmon, Eliza, 1787-1849)
        Mr. I. G. Schmidt ( Schmidt, Johann Georg, 1775-circa 1822)
        Miss Stephens ( Stephens, Catherine, 1794-1882)
        Mr. Tinney ( Tinney, Mr.)
        Mr. S. Wesley ( Wesley, Samuel, 1766-1837)
        Mr. Young ( Young, Charles Mayne, 1777-1856)
      - Covent Garden Theatre 29 April 1815, 1 broadside; 31 x 21 cm. (Box 1, Item 04)
        Reduced title transcription: Miss O’Neill’s night: Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden: This present Saturday, April 29 1815, will be acted the tragedy of the Grecian daughter … After which (2nd time) Milton's revived masque of Comus ... the original musick by Handel and Arne, with additions by Bishop, the overture by Cherubini. ... Mr. Kemble will perform on Monday, Coriolanus, on Thursday, The Stranger ... After which, the new melo-drama called The Forest of Bondy, or, The Dog of Mortargis … after which, The Sleep walker, to which will be added, Zembuca ... Printed by E. Macleish, 2 Bow Street.
        Kotzebue, August von, 1761-1819: Menschenhass und Reue. English (The Stranger)
        Murphy, Arthur, 1727-1805: Grecian daughter
        Milton, John, 1608-1674: Comus
        Oulton, Walley Chamberlain, 1770?-1820?: Sleep walker
        Pixérécourt, R.-C. Guilbert de (René-Charles Guilbert), 1773-1844: Chien de Montargis, ou, La forê^t de Bondy, as translated and adapted by Barrymore, W. (William), d. 1845
        Pocock, I. (Isaac), 1782-1835: Zembuca, or, The net-maker and his wife
        Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616: Coriolanus
        Mr. Abbott ( Abbott, William, 1789-1843)
        Arne ( Arne, Thomas Augustine, 1710-1778)
        Bishop ( Bishop, Henry R. (Henry Rowley), Sir, 1786-1855)
        Miss Bristow ( Bristow, Miss, 19th cent. )
        Mr. Broadhurst ( Broadhurst, Mr., fl. 1811)
        Cherubini ( Cherubini, Luigi, 1760-1842)
        Mr. Creswell ( Creswell, Mr.)
        Miss Foote ( Foote, Maria, 1797?-1867)
        Handel ( Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759)
        Mr. Jefferies ( Jefferies, Mr., fl. 1812)
        Mr. Kemble ( Kemble, John Philip, 1757-1823)
        Mr. King ( King, Mr.)
        Mrs. Liston ( Liston, Sarah, 1781-1854)
        Miss Luppino ( Luppino, Georgina, 1778-1832)
        E. Macleish ( Macleish, E. (Elizabeth))
        Miss Matthews ( Matthews, Catherine Mary)
        Mr. Murray ( Murray, Charles, 1754-1821)
        Mr. Norris ( Norris, William, d. 1816)
        Miss O'Neill ( O'Neill, Eliza, 1791-1872)
        Mrs. Parker ( Parker, Sophia, fl. 1763-1818)
        Mr. Sinclair ( Sinclair, John, 1791-1857)
        Mr. Slader ( Slader, Mr.)
        Mons. Soissons ( Soissons, M.)
        Mrs. Sterling ( Dixon, Clara Ann, fl. 1795-1822)
        Mr. Taylor ( Taylor, Mr.)
        Mr. Terry ( Terry, Daniel, 1782-1829)
        Mr. Treby ( Treby, Mr.)
      - Covent Garden Theatre 26 April 1837, 1 broadside; 34 x 22 cm. (Box 1, Item 05)
        Reduced title transcription: Theatre Royal, Covent Garden: This evening, Wednesday, April 26, 1837, will be presented (with the original music by Matthew Locke) Shakspeare’s tragedy of Macbeth ... After which, ninth time, an entirely new farce called the Modern Orpheus, or Music the food of love ... to conclude with the favorite operatic romance of Quasimodo, or, The gypsey girl of Notre Dame. Overture & music selected from the works of Carl Maria von Weber … To-morrow, Thursday (4th time) Brian Boroihme, or, The Maid or Erin: To conclude with … Mr. Sheridan Knowles’ historical play of William Tell … On Friday, will be performed (by particular desire) the play Ion, written by Mr. Serjeant Talfourd … after which, the original drama of The country squire … To conclude with The Modern Orpheus … On Monday will be produced a new historical tragedy to be called Strafford --- Mr. Osbaldiston has the honor of announcing … that his benefit will take place on Monday, the 8th of May on which occasion will be presented Shakspeare’s historical play of King Henry the Eighth ... S. G. Fairbrother, printer, Exeter Court
        Browning, Robert, 1812-1889: Strafford
        Dance, Charles, 1794-1863: Country squire
        Fitzball, Edward, 1792-1873: Quasimodo
        Knowles, James Sheridan, 1784-1862: Brian Boroihme
        Knowles, James Sheridan, 1784-1862: William Tell
        Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616: King Henry VIII
        Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616: Macbeth
        Talfourd, Thomas Noon, Sir, 1795-1854: Ion
        Webster, Benjamin, 1797-1882: Modern Orpheus
        Mr. Bender ( Bender, Mr., 19th cent.)
        Mr. G. Bennett ( Bennett, G. J. (George John), 1800-1879)
        Mr. Collins ( Collins, John, 1804-1874)
        Mr. Dale ( Dale, John, 1803-1872)
        Miss Deither ( Deither, Miss)
        S. G. Fairbrother ( Fairbrother, S. G. (Samuel Glover), fl. 1823-1855)
        Mr. W. Farren ( Farren, William, 1786-1861)
        Miss Helen Faucit ( Martin, Helena Faucit, 1814-1898 )
        Mrs. Garrick ( Garrick, Mrs., 19th cent.)
        Mrs. Glover ( Glover, Julia, 1779-1850)
        Mr. Harris ( Harris, Mr., 19th cent.)
        Mr. Huckel ( Huckel, Mr., 19th cent.)
        Mr. Jones ( possibly Jones, J. S. (Joseph Stevens), 1811-1877)
        Miss Lacy ( Lacy, Miss, 19th cent.)
        Miss Land ( Land, Miss, 19th cent.)
        Miss Lane ( Lane, Miss, 19th cent.)
        Miss Lee ( Lee, Henrietta Incledon, d. 1866)
        Matthew Locke ( Locke, Matthew, 1621 or 2-1677)
        Mr. Macready ( Macready, William Charles, 1793-1873)
        Miss Nicholson ( Nicholson, Miss, 19th cent.)
        Mr. Osbaldiston ( Osbaldiston, D. W. (David Webster), 1794-1850)
        Mr. Pritchard ( Pritchard, J. L. (John Langford), 1799-1850)
        Mr. Ransford ( Ransford, Edwin, 1805-1876)
        Mr. Ray ( Ray, J. W. (John William), d. 1871)
        Mr. Ross ( Ross, Mr., 19th cent.)
        Mr. Tilbury ( Tilbury, William Harries, 1806-1864)
        Mr. Thompson ( Thompson, Mr., 19th cent.)
        Mr. Vandenhoff ( Vandenhoff, John M., 1790-1861)
        Miss Vincent ( Vincent, Miss, 19th cent.)
        Carl Maria von Weber ( Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826)
        Mr. Webster ( Webster, Benjamin, 1797-1882)
        Mr. J. Webster ( Webster, John, 1810-1851)
        Mrs. W. West ( West, Sarah, d. 1876)
        Mr. Worrell ( Worrell, James, 1807-1865)
      - Royal Italian Opera (London, England) 29 March 1860, 1 broadside; 50 x 26 cm. (Box 1, Item 06)
        Reduced title transcription: Royal Italian Opera, Covent Garden: Mr. Frederick Gye having in the most generous spirit placed this theatre at the disposal of the council for a benefit in aid of the funds of the Royal Dramatic College, this evening, Thursday, March 29, 1860: the entertainments will commence … with the first act of Sir Bulwer Lytton’s play of Money: to be succeeded by the trial scene from Shakspeare’s Merchant of Venice …: after which, a selection from the late Douglas Jerrold’s nautical drama of Black-eyed Susan …: to be followed by a scene from the fifth act of Macbeth …: the screen scene from the fourth act of Sheridan’s comedy of School for scandal …: during the evening, a selection of vocal music …: J. Maddison Morton’s farce of Box & Cox … the celebrated Christy Minstrels will give selections from their popular entertainment: to conclude with the new and successful sketch, by Montague Williams and F. C. Burnand … entitled B. B. ... Printed by Peel’s Steam Machine, 74 New Cut, Lambeth.
        One act farce co-written by Burnand, F. C. (Francis Cowley), 1836-1917 and Williams, Montagu Stephen, 1835-1892: B. B.
        Jerrold, Douglas William, 1803-1857: Black-eyed Susan
        Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron, 1803-1873: Money
        Morton, John Maddison, 1811-1891: Box and Cox
        Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616: Merchant of Venice
        Sheridan, Richard Brinsley, 1751-1816: School for scandal
        Mr. Belford ( Belford, William Rowles, 1824-1881)
        Mr. Harcourt Bland ( Bland, Harcourt, d. 1875)
        Mr. J. B. Buckstone ( Buckstone, John Baldwin, 1802-1879)
        Miss Bufton ( Bufton, Eleanor, 1840-1893)
        Miss Bulmer ( Bulmer, Miss)
        F. C. Burnand ( Burnand, F. C. (Francis Cowley), 1836-1917)
        Mr. Walter Carle ( Carle, Walter, fl. 1861-1863)
        Mr. F. Charles ( Charles, F., Mr.)
        Mr. Chippendale ( Chippendale, William Henry, 1801-1888)
        Mr. Cockrell ( Cockrell, Mr.)
        Mr. G. Cooke ( Cooke, George, 1807-1863)
        Mr. H. Compton ( Compton, Henry, 1805-1877)
        Mr. T. P. Cooke ( Cooke, T. P. (Thomas Potter), 1786-1864)
        Mr. H. Cooper (possibly Cooper, Henry C., d. 1881)
        Christy Minstrels
        Mrs. W. S. Emden ( Emden, W. S., Mrs.)
        Mr. H. Farrell (probably Farrell, Henry, d. 1878)
        Mr. David Fisher ( Fisher, David, 1816-1887)
        Miss Glyn ( Glyn, Isabella, 1823-1889)
        Mrs. Griffiths ( Griffiths, Mrs., d. 1895)
        Mr. W. Harrison ( Harrison, William, 1813-1868)
        Madame Catherine Hayes ( Hayes, Catherine, 1818-1861)
        Mr. Howe (possibly Howe, J. B. (J. Burdett), 1828-1908)
        Miss Louise Keeley ( Keeley, Louise, 1833-1877)
        Mr. Keeley ( Keeley, Robert, 1793-1869)
        Mrs. H. Marston ( Marston, H., Mrs., 1808 or 9-1887)
        Mr. H. Marston ( Marston, Henry, 1804-1883)
        Mr. Charles Mathews ( Mathews, Charles James, 1803-1878)
        Mrs. Charles Mathews ( Mathews, Mrs. (Anne Jackson), 1782?-1869)
        Mr. F. Matthews ( Matthews, Frank, 1807-1871)
        Mr. A. Mellon ( Mellon, Alfred, 1820-1867)
        Mr. H. Mellon ( Mellon, Henry, 1808-1876)
        Mr. Edward Murray ( Murray, Edward, d. 1878)
        Mr. G. Peel ( Peel, G., Mr.)
        Peel’s Steam Machine (Firm)
        Mr. Phelps ( Phelps, Samuel, 1804-1878)
        Miss Louisa Pyne ( Pyne, Louisa Fanny, 1835-1904)
        Mr. H. Reeves ( Reeves, H., Mr.)
        Mr. F. Robson ( Robson, Frederick, 1821-1864)
        Royal Dramatic College (Woking, England)
        Mr. Ryder ( Ryder, John, 1814-1885)
        Miss Amy Sedgwick ( Sedgwick, Amy, 1835-1897)
        Madame Simon ( Simon, Madame)
        Mrs. Stephens ( Stephens, Mrs., 19th cent.)
        Mr. Edward Stirling ( Stirling, Edward, 1807-1894)
        Miss Stoker ( Stoker, Miss, 19th cent.)
        Mr. J. L. Toole ( Toole, John Lawrence, 1830-1906)
        Mr. B. Webster ( Webster, Benjamin, 1797-1882)
        Mr. Horace Wigan ( Wigan, Horace, 1818?-1885)
        Miss Woolgar (Mrs. A. Mellon) ( Mellon, Sarah Jane, 1824-1909)
        Mrs. Charles Young ( Vezin, Jane Elizabeth, 1827-1902)
    - Sadler's Wells Theatre, 1844-1862, 2. A. 2; Item 7-Item 15
      - Sadler's Wells Theatre (London, England) 11 August 1844, 1 broadside ([2] pages); 39 x 26 cm.; Presumably the first playbill for Sadler's Wells under the management of Samuel Phelps and Mary Warner. (Box 1, Item 07)
        Reduced title transcription: Theatre Royal, Sadler’s Wells: Lessee, Thomas Longden Greenwood … Under the management of Mrs. Warner and Mr. Phelps of the Theatres Royal, Drury Lane, Covent Garden, and Haymarket, Friday, August 16th, 1844, and Saturday, 17th, the performances will commence with the admired play of The Stranger … After which, the interlude of A Thumping legacy … To conclude with the laughable farce called Bachelors’ Buttons. Verso: Mrs. Warner and Mr. Phelps have embarked in the Management and Performance of Sadler's Wells Theatre, in the hope of eventually rendering it what a Theatre ought to be, a place for justly representing the works of our great Dramatic Poets. This undertaking is commenced at a time when the Stages which have been exclusively called "National" are closed, or devoted to very different objects from that of presenting the real Drama of England, … On Monday and Tuesday Shakspere’s tragedy of Hamlet with The Captain’s not a-miss and A Thumping legacy … it is in rehearsal and will speedily be produced … the tragedy of The Bridal Adapted for representation, with Three Original Scenes, written by James Sheridan Knowles, Esq., from the Maid’s Tragedy of Beaumont and Fletcher … Also in preparation … Massinger’s play of The City madam … S. G. Fairbrother and Son, Printers, 31, Bow Street, Covent Gard.